Guide to the Assistant Dean of Students for LGBT Student Support and Haven records,1979-2007.
Assistant Dean of Students for LGBT Student Support and Haven records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Assistant Dean of Students for LGBT Student Support and Haven records, 1979-2007.
37-1-3638
Cornell University. Assistant Dean of Students for LGBT Student Support and Haven.
1 cubic foot.
Printed materials, publications, correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Clippings, handouts, and posters and some email, correspondence, administrative files from LBGT Support and Haven, 1979-2007. Foam-core panel with introduction to Spring 2006 exhibit at Tatkon Center.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Starting in 1995, the Dean of Students' Office of Student Support had a staff person providing support for lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) students and students questioning or dealing with their sexual or gender identity. This unit offered peer counseling programs, peer-led support groups, and relevant events and programming. In the spring of 1999, Dean of Students staff brought the student-led support groups together under an administrative umbrella called Haven. An online peer mentoring service, faQ, was started in spring 2006.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Clippings, handouts, and posters and some email, correspondence, administrative files from LBGT Support and Haven, 1979-2007. Foam-core panel with introduction to Spring 2006 exhibit at Tatkon Center.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
Bisexual college students--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Gay college students--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Lesbian college students--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Transgender college students--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Homosexuality--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Bisexuality--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Gender identity--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Transsexuals--New York (State)--Ithaca .
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Peer Counseling [statement of purpose, Criteria for Counselors and sample intake sheet] (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Gay Counseling and Student Issues Clippings and Handouts, 1979-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- HIV/AIDS Information (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Transsexual Hormone Therapy and Surgery [clippings and handouts], 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- LGBT People of Color Clippings and Hanouts, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- GLBT Counseling and Student Issues Clippings and Handouts, Notes, 1979-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Greek Allies, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Working with GLB Greeks (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Coming Out to Parents, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Support Groups, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Transgender Handouts, Memos, Workshops, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Heterosexism Handouts and Clippings, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Daily Sun Clippings, 1999-2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Haven Training Packet, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Events, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Spring Events, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Fall Events, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Spring Events, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Haven Events, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Haven Posters, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Calendars, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Bookmarks (Box 1, Folder 22)
- 11 Filthy Gorgeous posters, assorted, February 2006 (Box 44)
- faQ Online student-to-student mentoring service poster (HAVEN) (Box 44)
- HAVEN (is an umbrella of student-led groups) poster (Box 44)
- Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender (LGBT) Staff and Faculty Celebrate "Gaypril" foamcore panel, April 2006 (Box 44)